I wanted to start things off by talking
about a tweet that I had which was
horrifying to be listening to a human
being speak and realize that they're
just a vessel for claude. This is the
second time I've done this tweet. And
the first time it did it did like Okay,
this second time around though, I guess
people might just be feeling it more. Uh
cuz it did like 700,000 views. And also,
one of the first replies I got to it was
a AI slop reply, which was like
>> drives me crazy.
>> They drive me crazy. It It's just the
the generic. This one was AI can help
organize ideas, but people still need
their own voice. That's what makes
conversations interesting. There's like
there's so much wrong with that as an AI
slop reply because it's just it's like
teetering on if it's real or not and
then I have to like go to the person's
profile and see that they replied to 10
tweets in a minute. And I just I replied
in all caps just ah like screaming uh
[laughter] because
>> I'm not going to lie, I just if I even
get the sense that someone has replied
to me or another tweet with AI, I just
block them like instant
>> I don't get it. It's annoying. Don't do
it. Uh audience uh I will block you. a
little hesitant on the blocking because
there's like enough non-neurotypical
people that reply to me that have the
same like phrasing unfortunately that I
like I feel bad for them. Um but so this
tweet I was watching a video and I
realized that like I was watching a
video and it just it it hit the claudism
of like it's not it's not an X, it's a
Y. It was like the dolly shot from Jaws
or whatever where you zoom out and you
realize you're just 100% reading Claude
slop. And I know it's really interesting
because we like there's this like
forcing function of just output output
output and you you do become a vessel
for Claude when you don't change the
output at all. is like a fascinating
thing in that like you've spent all of
this time building up your credibility
and like spent all the time building up
your credibility like who you are as a
person and I also don't know that people
people are never going to tell you that
you're putting out slop at least like
unless you like you you need close
friends to pull you aside and be like
>> if I ever am putting out something that
sounds like slop please just call me out
like
>> yeah right you don't know that you're
destroying your credibility
I guess from the from the perspective of
the person doing it, they're just like,
"Okay, more output is better, but you
really like lose the humanity in it a
little bit, which is tough."
>> Yeah. There's like kind of two
conversations around this that I've seen
popping up on Twitter. One is like what
you're talking about basically catching
people
using LLM to engage with other humans as
like the the proxy or the vessel for
that communication rather than um actual
humanto human communication where it
matters right like even like in things
like PR reviews like sometimes like you
don't want to be talking directly to
another person's agent like you want to
have that human discussion I think
another part is just like how verbose
and how strange these models talk and it
seems like it's getting worse or at
least more people are becoming sensitive
to it. I've recently been tweeting uh
about a skill that I picked up off the
the guy that made Planetator called Bro.
And this bro skill, it's like one line
or two two or three sentences is like
restate what you just said without using
technical jargon and just talk to me as
if I'm a human. And like it actually
does wonders. That's blown up a bunch of
times over the past couple weeks and
like now I see in random Twitter threads
where people are complaining about this
like, "Oh, just use the use the bro
scale. Uh like talk to me like a human."
And um obviously the other side of it is
like especially in the workplace like
there have been places like even in like
uh our our chat at work where like I can
distinctly tell where like someone just
pasted a LM response into like a thread
and sometimes like that can be
warranted. Like it kind of goes both
ways like if the person asking a
question or looking for information
doesn't put in effort. It's like I I
today now like I expect people to send
their agent out and do a bunch of work
before they just ask a easy lowhanging
question. But on the other side of that
is like if someone took the time to ask
like a good question in a human way. Uh
give them the respect and your time to
answer as a human as well.
>> No, at the very least you should say oh
by the way I just asked open code this
and this is what it says. I like people
who do that and say I don't know if it's
useful take it or leave it and you're
like okay fine like I'm approaching it
with the same context. I'm seeing a
bunch of tweets by the way about people
talking about claudisms. Couple of
things about this is well first of all
people are complaining about how Opus 5
is a bit too much in its responses like
the language itself has gotten so much
more dense loadbearing seams and
substrates and I'm like bro like okay
like no one has the time to like that
like well you need the bro skill. One of
my favorite short stories by one of my
favorite authors uh Jorge Louie Bourhees
uh is a story called um Thone Ukbar
Orbius Therius. Uh it's one of my
favorite short stories. It's in a short
story collection called Fixion. If you
want to read it, it's about some dude
discovers an encyclopedia about a fake
planet. And in it, it describes how uh
half the world believes in speaking in
nouns and half the world uh loves
speaking in verbs. And it becomes a big
uh mystery across the world to find out
who wrote this, where it comes from. And
it turns out to be like a prank by some
kind of aristocrat or some [__] like
that. But but what what ends up
happening is that the fiction takes over
the actual world and everyone becomes
like that and speaking in very specific
ways with like this verb specific or
noun specific and it destroys art,
history, anything of meaning because
everyone becomes this beige personality
and uh that book that story was written
a few hundred years ago and it's a
little scary how people are now starting
to speak like that. Two real world
examples. I think a couple of months
ago, some athlete I saw on TV announcing
his pick of team, which is a thing
Americans do, I guess.
>> Uh, but it was very obvious that he was
using the free version of chat GPT, like
you know, the language was very like he
was reading off his creed.
>> But my other favorite one is I think it
happened just a few weeks ago. some
legislator, a state senator or someone
was reading out a response and in the
middle of it he was like u here's a
version of this text that sounds better
suited for legislative assemblies and he
just kept talking [laughter]
>> uh if you can find this link or video. I
was I was like, "Holy sh" Like this is
corrupting like government and
everywhere. Like it's so it's so bad,
dude. Like just pure brain rot.
>> Like it's affecting Yeah, it's but it's
brain rot like for adults which is bad.
I mean it's definitely bad if they're
people are deciding policy based on
these things. Uh like substrate is going
to show up in an amendment soon enough.
That's what I'm saying. Like the word
substrate for sure,
>> man. I've I've heard human beings in
calls and in conversations and in other
videos on YouTube start using the word
substrate. And I'm positive I've never
heard that word used out of another
human being's mouth in before the last
four months. Let's get into the to the
show. Uh [laughter] welcome to uh the
next token. Today is Friday. No, it's
not. [laughter]
Damn it. I was just breaking the [__]
[laughter and gasps]
H. Well, let's get into uh the show.
Welcome to the next token. Today is
Monday, August 3rd, 2026. I'm Dylan
Malroy, and this is a podcast about
three software engineers who don't have
the time or energy to be hosting a
podcast.
>> I'm Ree. Uh I'm working on Executive.
>> Hi. Uh I'm Sunil Pi. Uh I work at
Cloudflare and so does Dylan. Uh and
they sponsored the show for us. So on
today's show, we are going to spend most
of our time talking about burnout. And
at the end, we're going to get into how
uh despite the times and the change in
our profession, how we still uh find joy
in our work. To kick things off, uh, I
had a tweet I put out a few weeks ago
where I kind of was tiptoeing about this
topic a little bit and we've certainly
talked about it a bit before on the show
and kind of alluded that this episode
was coming and that the three of us and
I think many others are kind of feeling
this way. So, a tweet I put out, I said,
"Y'all, I'm not going to lie, it's way
harder to get joy and satisfaction out
of building with AI than it was before.
constantly straddling burnout, being far
less immersed in hard problems, constant
context switching. I'm tired of the
uncertainty of where this is going and
how to do it well. And I I think that
resonated with people that got a lot of
attention. A lot of people,
wellrespected people kind of, you know,
replied to that tweet or quote tweeted
and, you know, said that that it
resonated with them and they were
experiencing um similar things. And I
don't know how and when we get past this
and I think um there's certainly
starting to be murmurss of this topic
going around kind of being more
mainstream. Uh for example
uh Scott Tolinsky from Syntax FM uh in
the past week or so put out a uh a
survey um called AI coding and mental
health which anyone listening please go
find that. I we'll put the link in the
in the show notes and uh fill that out
truthfully and earnestly. Um it's
anonymous. Um but I think that kind of
information is good. You know, I talked
about my workflow in our last episode
and
you know, I've worked pretty hard to get
to a place where I feel like I can do
good agentic engineering, but it is
definitely like a huge slog. And there's
a lot of uncertainty, which I think is
uh a big part of what is causing at
least for me the burnout or straddling
burnout. I wouldn't say I'm quite at the
point of burnout at this point, but you
don't know what the next model's going
to do. you don't know what the new
capabilities coming to harnesses is, how
it's going to change your workflow, then
just the dynamism of the models getting
even if you do the same workflow over
and over and over again, still getting
inconsistent results. Like that stuff
just I think at least for me wears me
down over time. So, uh curious how you
guys are feeling right now. The first
thing about the tweet that stood out to
me is actually like how popular it got
because it implies that
it's about like revealed versus stated
preference on Twitter. Otherwise,
everything is amazing and everyone's uh
building all these incredible things and
they're uh uh handling codecs from the
beach. But no, like I'm telling you
behind the scenes, everyone is just not
in a good place like right now. And
that's revealed by the likes and
retweets where they're like, "Okay,
fine. Like we get to this is the way
like I can kind of put myself out into
the world." And I'm so glad that a
respected engineer from a top tech
company is like just saying it out like
it is because you you clearly connected
with like so many people. We actually
looked this up. Thanks Chris. Uh and the
team uh and there's an official
definition for burnout. I didn't even
know by the way. The WHO defines burnout
as a syndrome conceptualized as
resulting from chronic workplace stress
that has not been successfully managed.
So it has three dimensions. Energy
depletion or exhaustion, increased
mental distance, negativis, negativism
or cynicism about the job and reduced
professional efficacy. Uh, I like that.
Uh, like one of my favorite uh Twitter
people, uh, Marcy Sutton, who doesn't
actually, I'm not sure whether she's on
Twitter anymore, she kept talking about
how,
>> uh, burnout uh, happens when you
recognize a problem and you can't really
change it.
>> So, it's not even clear to me that
what's happening is like real burnout,
but it resonates like so strongly. So,
there are some things that people kind
of get wrong, but we want to get them
right when we're talking about it. That
burnout is an occupational like
phenomenon. It's not a medical
condition. It's not like depression or
ADHD and a doctor so far can't like
diagnose you with burnout. Maybe a
therapist, I don't know, but like it's
definitely more felt. It's very
recognizable. So, there is that, but
it's not something that you can uh well,
you can't pop a pill for it, I guess,
unfortunately. Uh it's also explicitly
work related like it doesn't apply to
nonwork parts of life. I think that
would be closer to something like
executive dysfunction or something if
it's not actually related to work. It's
a problem caused by the job, not by the
person. Uh a key burnout researcher, uh
Christina Muslak, if I'm framing if I'm
spelling that right, frames burnout as a
mismatch between person and workplace,
which is what Marcy also says. uh
meaning there's a mismatch in the
workload, the sense of personal control,
rewards at work, sense of community at
work, fairness at work and uh personal
versus work values. Uh it's not personal
weakness. Uh it's a mismatch between the
job and the person. I think that's also
why sometimes like younger people get
affected by burnout more than older
people. like older people are just
either experienced enough to know how to
fix it soon enough or or they're just
detached from like office values where
they're like I'm just here to do a job,
bro. Like it's fine.
>> I think also maybe part of it is like
more tenured people have probably
statistically or potentially gone
through it in you know their younger
years or previous in their careers. I
know certainly there have been
two times where I've kind of felt pretty
actually burned out at work. not kind of
like how I am right now, kind of teeter
tottering in and out of it, but um and
like going having gone through those two
experiences earlier in my career, it's
made it easier to identify myself when
I'm starting to feel that way and know
that I need to like take a step back or
realign myself or just, you know, take a
moment to think about why I'm feeling
this way and what's causing it. One
thing that really stuck out to me in the
definition is uh actually two to the
point. So increased mental distance and
reduced professional efficacy.
I think those two really uh really I
don't know they strike me as like kind
of what I'm feeling. I probably have the
best work life balance I've had at maybe
any company at Cloudflare. like I'm not
pressured into long crazy hours. I don't
have any unreasonable expectations or
responsibility. Like I know the
direction I'm going in and the reason
why I'm doing it. Like that's all very
clear and I feel empowered and I uh am
behind the mission and the stuff we're
doing. But I think it's trying to
grapple with this new way of doing our
job. like it
our job is fundamentally different on a
day-to-day basis if you're someone who
has leaned into agent engineering which
many people in our industry are at this
point and the day-to-day just looks it's
a totally different job it's a totally
different skill set and to be efficient
at that job requires learning new skills
and I think that's what we've all been
trying to do uh over the past 12 to 6
months. And um
definitely having the reduction,
especially up front, in the efficacy of
my own work and being able to reliably
do my job in this new paradigm has been
taxing. and then having it change so
often and having unclear guidance and
best patterns from other uh you know
engineers in the field or just
information coming out of the labs just
isn't the way it works dayto-day. Um I
think has been making it really hard.
Um, two other articles I want to call
out is one from a former co-orker of
recent II, Ethan Naiser. He wrote on his
Substack a article called Not Holding
Back the Ocean. And I highly recommend
any software engineer listening to this
episode to go read it. It's it's very
short, but Ethan talks about in that
article uh grappling with the challenges
of or being a person whose identity is
very much tied to being a very good
software engineer and having spent the
past couple years of his career being a
very good software engineer and somebody
people look up to and having a
reputation for doing it well and then
having that change kind of overnight and
how jarring that is. And he he draws the
comparison of uh back in the day when
videographers and uh people creating
films used to manually cut film and then
it moved into the digital era. And uh he
kind of says something along the lines
of was it about actually physically
cutting film or was it about the end
product and solving challenges and
building good products? and he he he
kind of leans into like for me it's
always been about solving the challenges
and building good products and that
means that I need to get really good at
this this form of engineering and that's
the driving force behind all of it even
if it is ambiguous and confusing and
hard. Um I thought that was really good.
And then another article that got put
out last week was an article called the
dark knight of mathematics. And this was
a mathematician. I'm not sure their
name, but they wrote about kind of this
existential
dread or uh uncertainty around what the
world of mathematics looks like and what
that means for mathematicians. And he
talks about how the improvements in uh
OpenAI's models um have been you know
solving proofs and theorems and you know
ch or uh problems that haven't been
solved for you know a century. Um also
well worth the read
>> post about the math that the
mathematician wrote like I remember
reading it when you shared it with me
and it's a good post I think because oh
this this person is feeling like real
angst right now. I think software
engineers also felt it like a few months
ago. But this person like truly loves
mathematics and has always thought the
process of mathematics involved
mathematicians
and like finding all these edges of the
universe because it's such a pure
science
>> and he's seeing this collapse before his
very eyes now. And like it's clear that
these models are going to do much more
weirder stuff with maths. By the way,
like someone was talking about how well
maths is a very verifiable domain, but
even the verification by humans used to
be so hard. It might end up that the
proofs that these uh models come up with
might not be human verifiable in in very
soon like not even like in the far
future. Uh and I felt so bad. I felt
really badly for that. I wanted to buy
the dude a beer. I was like, "Okay,
yeah, like this is a person really
struggling." And I don't I like that's
burnout, I guess. like
>> yeah like how do you how do you convince
the next generation of mathematicians to
work on this?
>> There was a really uh like stark line he
had in there about for thousands of
years young mathematicians went through
all of the same process, the same
training for all of human history.
They've gone through the same exercise
of training into mathematics and
exploring the universe and quantifying
uh things and that is seemingly changing
at this moment. Something that has been
a part of human nature for since we've
been as a species. uh and like yeah I I
it's interesting that software engineers
and mathematicians are kind of the the
first two professions that are kind of
being profoundly impacted by AI and
uh I imagine over time this is only
going to continue happening to more and
more professions and I don't think I
don't know one I don't think as an
industry we're doing a very good job at
talking about the human impact of this
like you hear you know the headlines and
kind of the fear fear mongering or at
least the previous fear-mongering from
the AI labs about AI coming for your
jobs, but it is a hard thing to, you
know, I've spent the past 14 years being
a software engineer and doing the same
thing and getting very good at it and
now it's just changed and I don't think
there's a lot of good guidance on how to
deal with that.
>> There's also a really interesting
article on if LLMs were outputting
binaries instead of uh
>> Oh, yeah. I did read that
>> code
>> um to help empathize with what like
artists are going through where you
don't you don't have this like
collaboration with the machine. You just
have this thing that you're like
competing with. And that was also a
really interesting one. I don't know how
much that relates on the mathematics
side uh where I I I assume that it
disproving the conjectures is closer to
binaries than it is to code. I think it
applies more to software engineers than
it does to mathematicians by the way.
Like I think the reason everybody loved
like 4.5 4.6 so much especially in like
through Christmas and January because
that was before the hey we are going to
let the agent run for 12 hours and have
it do something. It was still very much
tactile. You were moving with the LLM
making changes etc etc. And that's the
thing like I I'll be honest like I don't
see what the point of AI generated music
is but I am so bullish on the idea of
um AI tools for making music. I did a
small demo of this earlier and it's
called pizza because I'm terrible at
like naming things. Um where I try to
put uh an agent interface right next to
a digital audio workstation where you
can still manipulate the dials etc. But
anything else you can actually like jump
into the agent and ask it to and you'll
see it like happen in front of you. It
actually like twists the dials and
changes sliders and things like that. A
that's not so threatening for musicians
because they're like, "Oh, it's just
another little thing I can use like in
my door while making music, but it still
means that I feel like my hands are in
the goo of like making the music even
though I'm using like an LLM to do it."
And I think 4.5 4.6 still did that. Uh,
I've still not done a 12-hour goal that
didn't produce anything but garbage. I'm
sorry. I I still need to like check it
every once in a while. And I wanted
I'm not saying I'm an artist. I am a
failed artist is what I am. But I still
want to feel in like I want to feel
connected to the code that I'm
generating. Like I I want to walk the
journey with the agent. I don't know.
Like I I I did have a 12-hour goal that
outputed
I tried the the game prompt the one that
was going around where the guy was like,
"Did you guys read the prompt on what
that one was? It was
>> I wonder what you're talking about."
>> Um so there was this uh I I forgot what
his name was. Um but he basically was
like, "Hey, go implement uh
Counterstrike." He was like, "Okay, Opus
Opus 5, go implement Counter-Strike." It
like does all of the 3D assets
programmatically. It does like the guns
programmatically. And the end result is
like decently competent output where you
get like an actual game you can go run
around in. So, I did that on like a I I
tweaked the prompt. The the prompt is
like super minimal. It's maybe like
three paragraphs, and by paragraphs, I
mean like two sentences each. Uh
>> Yeah. Yeah. And it's basically like,
hey, you're implementing XGAME, make it
photorealistic
sloop, verify your outputs, uh, and go
run autonomously. So, there's like a
bunch of interesting things to break
down there. The first one was that
I so like getting started with
programming. Uh, so I I gave it Mario
Kart to implement and I spent like six
months when I was like 18 trying to make
a VR version of Mario Kart
>> and trying to figure out the like cart
physics and how you can make it do loop
toloops and all this stuff. I So I was
like, "Okay, let's see if it can output
this." And it did pretty good pretty
good output in terms of like the cop
physics felt right and like the drifting
felt right and like can't even imagine
how useful of like a learning resource
that would have been in terms of like
when I was trying to learn how to do
these car physics years ago. I it was
just like me doing trial and error
trying to figure it out not having a
bunch of resources to turn to. Um,
the other thing is like
there's a weird thing I think there's a
thing that I've noticed of like when you
try and interject into what the model is
doing because the like as dumb as the
slashloop verify your work make it great
prompt is it does actually work very
well. Uh, and I think that there's an
interesting thing there in terms of like
when you give the agent the ability to
verify its own work and test its own
work and do all that, you get better
outputs. Um, but the thing about all of
these like game prompts is you're not
like interjecting your own like taste
and g like game design and all of this
into the prompt. The LLM is just making
like what it it wants to make. And I
think that once you like try and
interject into it, you like start to
fight the training data and that's where
your outputs get worse. There's a bunch
of interesting things. So
>> I feel almost opposite that like
I need to interject and steer to get the
results that good results that I need.
I I maybe it's this like loop this like
there's like the valley of despair where
like if you're trying to do very
>> I know
>> where if you're trying to do like very
agentic written software that when you
try and interject into the agentic
written software then it's more painful.
But if you're like more [clears throat]
using it as like a typing replacement,
then the interjection works versus like
if you're letting it run and burn tokens
and verify itself and all that, then it
you will al also get good results. I
don't know. People say you get good
results. I'm
I'm yet to see like I'm yet to be
convinced. It's funny that Sil you
talked about uh starting to work more
closely alongside an agent. Like you
talked about building that sound program
and having an agent side by side. I
actually in the like this weekend I was
like I I cannot even with my workflow
last time I I have started now just like
opening up like a markdown document that
I write in and have the agent watch. I
just iterate back and forth in that.
It's similar to the techspec before, but
like I correct it immediately and I've
just been using like Luna to make it
super fast and have that very fast back
and forth with it. And like that seems
to be working well, but it's also like
like I talked about last time, a lot
more effort um to to get it, which
paradoxically the most annoying thing of
uh this time period is that like as
exhausting and as ambiguous and dynamic
as these tools are, like I am actually
more productive for better or worse,
like I am outputting more work and work
that I'm the quality
that I'm proud of and can put my name
on, but it's exhausting uh for a lot of
the reasons we've outlined. Um yeah, I'm
curious to know like how how have you
been dealing with this?
>> I think we ended last time show with me
saying that I'm like burnt out as hell.
So like since then I've actually taken
like two weeks of leave
>> and it was amazing. Um I uh Spider-Man
movie was good by the way. I also watch
movies in a very specific way that I
recommend other people do which is you
go for the morning show on a weekday and
it's like empty which means
>> you can like manspread over like the
couch. I do the everyman and they have
couches there.
>> Uh and uh you get a big popcorn and like
I I really like watching movies in
slightly empty theaters. Like I love it.
>> My favorite thing there is a period of
time in my life where on Sunday mornings
uh I would go to see a movie by myself.
I would pick up Duncan. I would just go
in and I would have a coffee. I would
have a bacon, egg, and cheese and hash
browns. I'd be like the only person in
the theater. It was amazing. 10 out of
10. Recommend.
>> And I get it. Like people with real real
jobs. No, we have real jobs. Uh with
like jobs, families, they need to like
synchronize and but they end up going
like for the later shows. I'm just
saying like if you can go alone to like
uh and you get like discounts also like
for those shows. Watching Spider-Man
like that was amazing. like you should
do it. It did give me like a little bit
of time to like think about uh like what
I want and how and I'm I work on the
Cloudflare agents team in Cloudflare.
The team is amazing. Like we have like
hitters on it and we've been doing
really well. Cloudflare's agent story is
like doing really well. Well, the agents
SDK stuff uh that's what we do. So, it's
not like I have like my values are so
aligned with the company's values. Oh,
I'm being such a company shell here.
Take it, take take it or leave it,
right? Uh so where exactly am I finding
the burnout from? Chris actually uh
thanks Chris Higgins. Uh he linked uh he
linked us to uh this article about um
his name is Glyph Lefkowitz. He's come
up with a formula. It's called the
futsing fraction uh that and it's got a
whole bunch of factors for uh the
expected value when you interact with
one of these coding agents inference
machines and depending on different
values based on like how much time you
spend on it what probability it's going
to give you the right amount of uh right
answer the cost per inference loop etc
etc whether it's actually worth uh
spending your time with these things
like because if you get a fraction
that's on the wrong side of one then you
are probably better off doing it by
yourself but it's hard to argue in the
face of just lines of code like it is
probably worth the time and money spent
on it uh but the thing that I kept
thinking about was the fraction and
frameworks like that don't calculate the
toll that it takes on human beings
especially when you do it like many
times in a row I was feeling similar
burnout in December last year which is
why I missed the entire Christmas uh New
Year's uh wibe extravaganza by the way.
Uh uh and then I came and I was glad
because I watched a [__] ton of pyro and
I walked around in my nice jacket. I
think that might be what is happening to
me which is it it's burnout faced by
like uncertainty of the job or like what
what is the role of code now? Like code
used to be like for building products.
Now, Charlie Marsh had a great tweet,
the guy who made Astral. He was talking
about how uh you should be ready to
build something
and commit to building something that
will be obsolete with like very soon.
Like you should build products and
features uh that will actually not be
relevant in a couple of months because
it's like very needed at the moment. But
the model company or the harness or even
just the desire for the feature it might
just be a solved problem will disappear
very very quickly. I think this is the
thing about takeoff right it's not just
that these things are uh happening
quickly but all the emotions and
consequences are also being like
compressed. Of course software used
would get uh obsoleted like yeah there's
like very little software from 20 years
ago that like lasts now or whatever it
is. Well, some of it still does,
>> but like a year ago,
>> that sort of software was like a bash
script that we used to run in CI/CD or
fix some local problem or
>> it wasn't entire features or entire
products or entire tech stacks just
getting changed 3 months from now. It
just all came on so quickly that like
>> there is no writing or there is no
precedence for how to plan and deal with
that.
>> I'll give you another example that I
faced just today by the way. So, we have
a little over a hundred open issues on
the agents repo. And we were like, "Oh,
we need to do an issue triage and we
need to like talk about who like what
we're going to do with all of these
issues." And previously that would be
like an hourong call where the team
would jump in like we'd start labeling
stuff. Bro, have you used Codex computer
use? It's amazing.
>> And I was like, "Hey, Cod Codex." Yeah.
Hey, Codc. Oh, yeah. We spoke about
this. It ordered you a [__] Apple
remote last time. like literally got
delivered during the show which was uh
quite funny. So I just dumped the repo.
I was like, "Hey, can you like classify
these issues? Tell me which ones are
valid, which ones uh can you group them
by theme?"
>> And it did it all for me in 10 minutes.
The thing is I really enjoyed those
issue triage meetings because I used to
get to like I work remote so I used to
hang out with my team for an hour
talking about what is important to us,
how we used to what we feel about this,
how do we sequence like
>> that process was healthy for reasons
other than just managing the repository
and that's not a thing. So,
>> we we were going to record this episode
last Friday, uh, but we had to
reschedule because, uh, I had a
production incident with artifacts and
like what you're talking about hit me
real hard during that. It wasn't like a
particularly bad incident. It was just
some data we had to clean up. But I
spent the day basically like almost 12
hours on a call with the other two
people on my team. And like I kind of
just realized that like I've been
working remote since the before times of
COVID. I've been remote since 2016. Uh
so I'm I'm very I've been doing it for a
decade I guess and I'm very used to
working remote. I'm very effective at uh
socializing remotely and you know
merging into remote culture. These are
things I'm very comfortable with. But I
do think there is a stark difference
between now
and a year ago in how I'm collaborating
with people on my team in in an organ.
The company like I can do much larger
swaths of work independently by myself
without needing other feedback for
longer periods of time. And that like
the the isolation uh is worse than it's
ever been. And part of that is probably
recalibrating and being like, okay, I
need to like go out of my way to, you
know, engage more and be more explicit
and intentional about that. But also
like it is the fact that like especially
on more senior teams, like there is way
more autonomy now uh to do larger work
for longer periods of times without
interacting with teammates remotely. And
I think that's that's definitely I I
hadn't considered that playing into the
way I felt until Friday, but certainly I
think that's that's part of it.
>> I assume those 12 hours were the longest
you had spent with these people in like
so long for the exact same
>> dude. I'm not going to lie, despite it
being an incident, like I had a great
day on Friday. Like I got to hang out
and solve problems with people I love
hanging out and working with.
>> It means that startups are actually also
smaller. It means that teams are smaller
and like you said like people work
independently for way longer periods of
time. Is that obsoleted by coding? Like
is the before thing obsoleted by coding
agents? I guess so. Like it's fine. We
had Steve James on our team who's now
left and he's doing his own startup and
he was so incredible at reviewing PRs
like he like last year he would catch
things that LLMs wouldn't. I'm sorry to
say I think like LLMs have gotten like
better than him now. Like I think they
catch the edge cases really well now.
>> The customtailored review agent is when
you get that dialed in it it's it's
pretty good. They can be pretty good.
This is one of my problems with LLMs
though, or not problems with LLMs, but
there's like there's a weird thing with
LLMs where some I feel like I'm not
using enough inference at times where
it's like, oh, this uh
like this issue in production could have
been caught if you had an agent that was
monitoring your logs or this
>> issue if you go run this pull request
back through a review agent, oh, this
review agent would have caught it. And
that's one of my like problems with the
but then you like I feel like you're
building up this like house of
non-deterministic cards of uh inference
and I really like it's a weird unnatural
way of working. Uh but you're building
on all this non-determinism but then
it's like it's not like you're you had
had a deterministic thing that you were
replacing. Like humans weren't aren't
deterministic.
Uh but at the same time it's it's very
>> it was good having a human who knew
where the skeletons were buried. Right
now you you're not sure it's going to
pop up.
>> It's actually funny that you say that
because like the incident on Friday I am
so glad that the three of us were
familiar with the codebase and able to
like we I mean we used the agent. The
incident that happened to us on Friday
would have been at least a week-l long
recovery pre- aent, but being able to
have it gre through click house and go
through all our workers observability
and query a bunch of different SQLite
databases and like have that we caught
the problem really quickly. And then we
were able to aggregate all the data from
all the data sources that we needed
within a hour or two and figure out what
we needed to do and where the problem
was coming from and how to solve it. And
then we got to build tools. We built a
bunch of scripts to go do data repair
and then had agents run and monitor
those. And like that would have been at
least a weekl long process a year ago.
Um but at the same time the actual
knowing how to solve the problem
and the right correction, I don't think
agents would have arrived at it would
have been some brute force solution that
probably would have caused more problems
or incidents than it was worth. But
because the three of us knew the
codebase was like and the domain matter
and where the code was and the SQLite
database schemas it was like okay having
a scalpel right like you could be very
precise about the the fix and knowing
where the problem was and like if
anything that's made me want to read
every line of code even more because
I've now lived an incident caused by an
agent and then having to go fix it and
it would have been yeah it would have
been really bad if I didn't know the
code. What caused the problem?
>> One of the developers uh was like asked
his agent like why is why is why is the
chart spiking? And then it turned out
Luna had uh he was doing some design
work on a prototype and Luna had
deployed straight to prod from his
machine rather than going through uh we
have a tool called release manager which
does basically like blue green uh health
mediated deployments and uh part of that
it ran a migration on a database that
did not have like the other end of
writing to it and it uh broke a bunch of
data. not only did an LLM cause it, it
also like dramatically helped fix it and
have it go much more quickly. And like
that could have, you know, there's a a
billion different ways like that could
have been a bad migration push by a
developer too. Um,
>> so not to like discredit LMS there, but
>> you know the like spiky intelligence. I
I love the the chart of spiky
intelligence where it shows like this is
the circle and it has these like huge
spikes and then these like troughs. They
so heavily fall into that. Also like
they're not able to like they miss the
ability to like understand problem
spaces or something something like that
if that makes sense. you'll be working
with them and they'll jump to proposing
a solution and like I can look at the
solution that they proposed and I'm like
well you're not considering multiple
accounts or you're not considering
there's this like whole world of issues
you're not considering
>> and like that compounds because like you
can correct them on any one piece of
work but then it's like a a goldfish it
just forgets the next session which like
>> ironically I think is like kind of an
important thing right now with how
context works. But like that's one of
the things that's bothering me the most
right now and that like I'm actively
trying to find ways to
uh improve is just like I'm so tired of
telling the LMS the same things and
catching the same sorts of problems and
it's like what is the definition of
insanity? Doing like the same thing over
and over again and expecting different
results. Like I'm like hitting my
breaking point. Like I'm trying to
capture all my feedback review and just
like be able to I don't know if it's
skills. I don't know if it's a customer
review agent. I don't know if it's
loops, but like it is getting
exhausting. My soft my PR review looks a
little bit like that. And we might go
into it a little bit when we do our
workflow episodes. Uh please look for
edge cases. One of my favorites is can
you look for things you might not have
looked for? which is just the stupidest
thing to tell an LLM, which is
>> But it works. I
>> Yeah, it works every single It works
every time, by the way. Like, it works
every single
>> That one works slashdop like telling the
agent to write the code better. That one
works.
>> That's negging, dude. That's negging of
a coding agent where you're like, "Yeah,
you you sound I can't I cannot believe
that I cannot believe that I can tell
the magic box to write better code and
it will write better code."
>> I [laughter] This is It's the dumbest.
Do you know like how far we've fallen?
[laughter]
If that works.
[snorts] This is like when you go to a
restaurant and you ask for everyone
orders food and one person says, "Could
you bring mine in a clean plate and
everyone's mad at you because they're
like, "What do you think?" And then the
waiter comes back and like, "Who's the
one who asked for the clean plate?"
Like, I got it for you. Uh,
>> is that just how they they serve food in
England on dirty plates?
>> I mean, half this country still eats
like the war is [snorts] going on. Do
you know what a chipped butty is, my
guys?
>> Like, it's French fries in bread. It's
French fries in in bread. It's a French
fry sandwich. And I'm like, come come
on, you guys. I I I assume at this point
someone's going to put up a chip buddy
picture in the video version of this.
Make sure it's in my hands right here. A
chip buddy. Um,
>> do you like Do you like pasties? No.
>> I love pasties, though.
>> Okay. That's By the way, I like British
food. Just so we're clear. I like
British food. Some of it is
embarrassing. There's like too much
carbs and stuff. The chip buddy one
throws me off. My like my brother-in-law
loves those. He's like, "Bro, when you
when you're having another chip buddy?"
I'm like, "Dude, I just I'm it's uh no
chip buddies."
>> So, Sunil, I I want to I want to ask a
bit more uh deeply here. Like, what what
do you think in your day-to-day because
we've we've both already clarified that
like the culture at Cloudflare is great.
We're not being overworked. We're not
having unrealistic timelines or pressure
put on us. like what do you
think has led or been the the cause of
your your current burnout?
>> I have a couple of theories. Uh some of
them are I mean they're all pretty
self-centered, but I might as well say
it. A lot of my identity as a software
developer, right, comes from being like
good at my job.
>> Yep.
>> Like be being the guy that they go to,
you know, like, oh, here's a hard
problem. Let's put Sunil on it because
he's he's the guy. I mean like sure like
I wield these machines really well but
I'm not the guy anymore right like I
feel like a part of my identity like oh
me being a little special baby that that
image is under attack the way I try to
counter is counter it is by doing more
of it where I'm like okay I'm going to
work like even harder I'm going to build
this incredible serverless hardness
which I'm again just so we clear so
proud of the work project think is
amazing and the cloudflare agents SDK
like definitely some of the best work
I've done in my life, in my entire
career. But it's still not me, dog. Like
uh I'm not am I am I doing the brush
strokes or am I using a remote control
and watching a TV play what episodes I
wanted to play? So I think that's I
think that's part of it.
The second is I'm very worried for the
industry and I think I'm taking it on to
myself. I've written about this before
and I worry about what we are doing
especially to like juniors in the
industry and I wonder if I'm
contributing to it right like oh I'm set
by the way uh what I said last time I'm
spitting out 50 60 70,000 lines of code
a week when a junior hears this do they
freak out like do they get scared like
is that what's expected of them
>> and I want to be like no it's not
expected of you but do I believe that
like do I actually like isn't that going
to be an expectation like eventually
like uh and they're doing it in a
context where they have very little
mentoring like they don't have the same
model where they get to sit next to a
senior engineer in an office and
literally ape the keystrokes right
>> yep
>> uh like you said like senior engineers
are all spending their time now just
locked in like at work [__] out like
a whole bunch of code so like I said
like this is all very self-centered and
not but it does like affect me and and
then I started wondering ing about
whether
whether I'm even capable of recognizing
whether I'm building the right thing.
>> Uh, and this one is a little weirder
because like I said, like I
uh the American frontier was not found
by patting the bison on the back and
pointing them in a direction, right?
Like people died along the way, like
discovering the new world and stuff. It
feels like there's no struggle left in
that anymore. I like just the way I
don't believe songs should be made like
that. Maybe software shouldn't be built
like that. So there is a little bit of
that and then I just I I think like that
compounded with being tired and being
like remote maybe like being remote
actually affected it where I couldn't go
and the first thing I did as soon as I
went on leave was I went to London and I
had a team lunch and I had beers with
them and I like hung out on my leave and
it was great. I like love them. It was
such a good time. I wonder is being
remote something that affects it maybe
not because I have been able to like
build very very big things. So it did
take me a couple of weeks and I'm back
literally today by the way Monday and I
feel great because I think I was
reminded I spent the last couple of
weeks thinking what actually does give
me joy and happiness from
>> uh building recognizing that was a very
big part of me coming back being all
happy and cheerful. So, I feel really
good. I feel really good now, just so we
are clear. But I think it did take me
two weeks of soulsearching and watching
late night TV to do so. I started
watching the four seasons on Netflix
because Tina Fay is a genius and she can
do no wrong. It was a It was a good
show. It was a good show.
I'm curious what maybe end on a more
positive note to go over like what does
um what like we are still like enjoying
on software development and uh what that
looks like on my end. I've just been
I've been having a lot of fun with like
personal software like the
it it still hasn't clicked in a way that
like it sticks around in my life. Uh but
like I had an agent go and like scrape
HelloFresh's uh recipes and like make me
a a website viewer for that. And then
like I made like a thing that let my
friends message my agent. Uh so that way
our agents could like chat with each
other. And that one was like little like
spark joy moments of when you get
something that's working. Uh was a lot
of fun
>> for me. I think kind of paradoxically
the one of the things that is bringing
me joy despite a lot of this uncertainty
and ambiguity and straddling some
burnout is that like the moments where I
do end up creating something really good
that I'm proud of with AI or a workflow
that I've been working on just works and
produces something great or I I find a
way to steer the agent better and
actually produce a good result. Like
that's that's rewarding in the same way
that like problem solving was the rest
of my career. And that's that gives me
hope. Uh that gives me like I do feel
like there is a a light at the end of
the tunnel where there is
less dynamism and there is better
tooling and more clear best practices
and ways to be the person that uh others
come to uh for solving hard problems. So
that that feels really good when it
happens despite like the amount of work
and struggle uh getting there at the
moment. Also like Reese like building
personal software has been great like
there was a a couple tweets circulating
last week about uh recipes like these
engineering recipes where it was like
this table and it was like very like
methodical and like I built a little app
to take any recipe and convert it into
an image like that and like that was
awesome. I used that cook to cook twice
this weekend. Um, so things like that is
really really rewarding. I've also had
the opportunity to talk to a couple
interns in the past two weeks at
Cloudflare and you know I like you
talked about Sunnil like I I am very
worried about how we level up uh junior
devs and interns and mid-level devs and
uh I think I walked away from those
conversations with a bit more optimism
than I went into them with. Uh I think
that you're certainly feeling uh
uncertainty and not I mean how would
they know how to navigate this industry
anyways? But um the curiosity
is what struck me and that was still
there and I think as long as the
curiosity of younger devs persists and
is like the thing that drives them
forward I think they'll figure it out
even if it's not the same conventional
path we went down. So know what uh what
is bringing you joy in your your
day-to-day or how can people uh who may
be feeling burnout kind of take a step
back and recover.
>> So my favorite feeling about making
software which is true today as it was
on day one is uh someone using it and
like being happy with it. Uh, and this
could be a developer using a dev tool
that I made or someone using a website
that I made and someone and just telling
me like, and I again it sounds like I
love it when people praise me, but I do
love it when people praise me, but it's
not even the praise. People talk about
it specifically like, "Hey, I used your
thing and it worked great. Thank you,
>> bro. That feeling unparalleled. Oh my
god, bottle it up." Like, is is this
what hard drugs make you feel like? I
imagine so like it must [laughter] it
must be something like this because holy
[__] um that feeling like today still
gives me like shivers when someone says
that to me.
>> Uh they will thank they will thank like
like one of the reasons I became the
durable object guy was because I thought
the DX was kind of [__] and then I spent
5 years trying to fix it and then
someone will use my thing and like oh
this made durable objects a lot easier
to use. Thank you. I'm like, "Oh my god,
that yes, that's the big one for me."
>> Dude, I use agent SDK for every durable
object I make, whether it's AI or agents
or not.
>> Thank you.
>> You made my day, my guy. That's all I
care about.
>> That is kind of And that that kind of
goes back to Ethan's article, too. It's
like the end of the day, what really I
think probably drives all three of us is
building good products and solving hard
challenges and watching people use the
results of that.
>> I was on Kod's podcast recently
>> and like some of my favorite software
I've ever made has not been huge scale.
It's been like tiny back office tools
that I was able to like walk down the
hallway and see some business analyst
using and it just made their day-to-day
10 times better. Like best feeling.
All right, y'all. Uh, that's the next
token episode 3. We'll be back in two
weeks with more opinions, predictions,
maybe Reese or Sunnil's workflow and how
they're working with AI and whatever
blows up in the news. In the meantime,
follow the show uh wherever you're
watching or listening and tell us uh
what you think in the comments.
>> Thank you.
>> Cheers. We know some of this is kind of
heavy. Uh and if you're somewhere in
burnout like yourself, trust me, it's
not you. It's it's definitely the job.
Even the people who love this stuff a
lot [music] are renegotiating how they
do it. Especially at a time when things
are changing like even like every 3
months. It means you have to change it
like four times a year. Who knows?
>> Y
>> we joke a lot on the show and like
burnout is real. Uh if you're feeling
overwhelmed and like struggling like
support is available. We'll share some
of these on-screen resources right now
and there are links also in the show
notes and in the description both on
audio and video. Uh but definitely like
seek help. It can be with your friends,
your family or professional help. Uh
highly recommended. Uh all right. Uh
thanks and see you all next time.